Open ilastik and choose the Carving workflow
Load your dataset (here a volume of mouse retina EM data, Winfried Denk, et al.)
Go to the Preprocessing applet and choose the right boundary type for your data
Toggle Filtered Data layer to check if the computed boundaries correspond to the edges in the image
Change the sigma of the smoothing kernel if the boundary map is too noisy or overly smooth
Click the Run button to apply preprocessing to your data
Go to the Labeling applet and mark the object of interest with an 'Object' seed and the outside with a 'Background' seed
Click Segment to start a seeded watershed segmentation
Scroll over your data and refine segmentation
Have a closer look at the 3D view of your object
Save the segmented object
See already segmented objects by enabling the Completed Segments overlay
Segment another object
Show both objects in 3D
Save the second object
Click Completed Segments to show segmented objects
Export mesh for 'object02'