Choose a workflow: Here we choose "Cell Density Counting"
Choose where to save your ilastik project
Add your data [VisRec Project, University of Oxford]
Select a set of features
Label the objects you want to count
Adjust the "Sigma" value to fit your data, if necessary
Label the background as well
Enable "Live Update" to train a classifier with the current labels
In the list of image layers you can adjust the current view
Add boxes to verify the trained classifier and adjust your labels and/or the chosen "Sigma"
Click "Update total Density" to get the total count estimate for the current view
"Choose Export Image Settings... "
Adjust export settings like "Subregion", ...
various data transformations, ...
and the output file and format
Finally you can either "Export All" datasets at once or export each dataset individually
In the list of image viewers you can checkout a preview, as well as the exported data